出门打，我是猛抬头
I lift up my head
眼前来到了风月楼
Here I am at the Fengyue Brothel
风月楼里的姑娘好
The girls are lovely here
一个倒比一个娇
All very charming
有翠红，有小小
Cuihong, Xiaoxiao
海仙，银娣还有金宝
Haixian, Yindi and Jinbao
杏核眼是真风骚
Big eyes
扬柳腰是真苗条
Slim waists
她的前边高后边翘
Gorgeous figures
该大的地方大，是该小的地方小
Perfect! All the right curves in right places
楼上楼下，前院后院的姑娘们
Girls, upstairs downstairs, front and back courtyards
都出来见客了
Come out to greet the guests
来了…
They're here
海棠、晴雯
Haitang, Qingwen
小玉、美宝、美红
Xiaoyu, Meibao, Meihong
国花、小娟、玉兰
Guohua, Xiaojuan, Yulan
迎春、美芳、惠娟
Yingchun, Meifang, Huijuan
怎么回事？
What's going on?
一个是王三公子，一个是玉堂春
They are like Romeo and Juliet
两个人上洋劲
They've got hearts for each other
上什么洋劲？到底怎么回事？
Really?
那个姓王的在这儿住了一个多月
Mr. Wang has been here for over a month
跟金宝打得火热
He has very much taken to Jinbao
真刀真枪的跟真的一样
They seem serious
如今带来的钱全都花光了
He has spent all his money
说今儿个回上海家里拿钱去
He'll go back home in Shanghai to get more
两个人哭得跟个泪人似的
Crying their eyes out
山盟海誓，交换表记呢？
Exchanging their vows, and love tokens
表记？什么表记？
What kind of love tokens?
小王说是要敲根门牙下来
Mr. Wang said he'll take out a tooth
表示非金宝不娶
He will marry no one but Jinbao
金宝也要剪下一卷头发下来
And Jinbao will cut off her hair
说是生是王家人死是王家鬼
She said she'll be his wife for sure
我呀这就替她拿剪刀去
I'm getting her a pair of scissors
是不是真的？
Did she mean it?
我们这儿是风月楼
This is the Fengyue Brothel
那边是虫二阁
That's the Chonger Room
说的是风月无边
Named after the famous brothel
这边是因受阁
Over here is the Yinshuo Room
说的是恩爱无心
Meaning relaxed so to speak
真真假假，虚虚实实
Things are true and false at the same time
不是，我问拔牙是不是真的？
No, I meant the tooth
牙？牙怎么不是真的？
Of course
你…你真的拔了？
You... have done it?
真的，我说得到做得到
Yes, a word is a word
金宝，我…我全是真的
Jinbao, I'm serious about you
小王，我心好疼
Xiaowang, my heart aches
我也好疼呀
And I'm in pain too
怎么？真的剪哪？
She's doing this for real?
可不，你当是你哪
Of course not
小姑娘唱小曲，假情假意
You can't trust a prostitute
阔少爷花大钱，真动真心
The rich customer has fallen in love
金宝，你真的把它剪了？
Jinbao, have you cut your hair?
你带着它，就像带着我一样
Take this; you'll know I'm always with you
金宝
Jinbao
宝…宝贝…
My precious...
你放心，我一到上海
Don't worry, once I arrive in Shanghai
跟爹妈说明白了
...I'll let my parents know
我马上带钱回来接你出去
I'll come back for you
记着我要你带的东西
Remember to bring the things I want
我记得
Yes I will
就是金山银山我也把它搬回来
Mountains of gold, silver, anything you want
翠莲、小凤
Baozhu, Cuilian, Xiaofeng
小翠、秋红
Xiaocui, Qiuhong
老板，全来齐了
They're all here, sirs
有的有客的，有的出条子的
Some have customers, some are escorts
听说你们这儿新来了三个
I heard there are three new girls
有一个陶记窑什么的老板娘？
One is the lady boss of a pottery store?
听说是大龙船打滚，浪大得很
I heard she's quite a woman
您说的是海仙哪
You meant Haixian?
是呀，叫来看看
Yes, call her here
为了养汉把老公给气死了
Because of her affairs her husband died
真的？
Really?
叫来看看
Call her
她有很多客人
She's very popular
我们等她
We'll wait
不行，有好几位等着呢，来不了
There's a long list; maybe not today
这么红？
She's so popular?
敢情，我告诉您哪
Yes, let me tell you
床上跟床下真有她的一套
She's good in bed, and off the bed too
就在隔壁
Right next door
不要嘛…死相
Stop it
你这个人，给个脸就上鼻梁
Why are you in such a hurry?
现在可不止上鼻梁了
I can't wait
干什么？动真格的？
Are you for real?
说真的，都说你是个养汉精
The word is that you cheated on your husband
到底是不是？
Is that the truth?
你们男人个个都是花心萝卜
All men cheat
整天在外头拈花惹草
...on their wives. And then
反而说老婆招蜂引蝶
...you go around accusing wives to be promiscuous
说来听听，到底是怎么回事？
Tell me what happened
养汉
Cheating on husbands
女人生下来就比男人矮半截
It's so unfair
这年头女人养汉叫人捉住了
If a woman is caught cheating
就活活打死
She got beaten to death
嫁个不中用的丈夫就算你倒霉
Marriage to a useless guy is so unfortunate
老板娘…
Lady boss...
吓我一跳
Hey, you scared me!
怎么了？在想什么呢？
What were you thinking about?
长得倒蛮登样的
She's quite pretty
好好的人，养汉！
Can't believe she cheated on her husband
可不是嘛，这种人就应该千刀万剐
Right, she deserves to be cut into pieces
买什么？
What do you want to buy?
夜壶
A chamber pot
大锤不留神，把夜壶给砸碎了
My husband broke it
你的尺码，她怎么那么清楚？
How come she knows your size?
啊！
Oh!
啊什么？
What?
你想到哪儿去了？
What are you talking about?
你又不是第一次买
Ain't the first time you buying a chamber pot from her
王大锤
Wang Dachui
刁师爷
Lawyer Diao...
有笔吗？
You have a pen?
笔？
A pen?
记帐用的
To write down my accounts
笔呀，我是用炭条的
I use charcoal
老板娘
Lady boss...
刁师爷
Lawyer Diao...
借笔？
Could I borrow a pen?
什么？
What?
笔，写字的笔
A pen
笔，说清楚点嘛
Speak clearly
怎么，又替人写状子？
So, working on a new case?
是呀，就是刚才那一档
Yes, that case
替原告写呀？
For the plaintiff?
原告有什么好写的
No
捉奸捉双，送到县衙里
Caught in the act, sent to the judge
准判个斩立决
Sentenced to be beheaded
替被告写呀？
For the defendant?
有用吗？
Can you help?
没用我们吃什么
Of course, otherwise I won't get paid
我又不会卖夜壶
I don't sell chamber pots
放屁
Shut up
卖夜壶就吃夜壶呀
Eat chamber pots
夜壶有什么好吃？
What's there to eat?
你见过吃香蕉连皮一块吃的吗？
Do you eat a banana with the skin?
你们这些师爷一张嘴就强词夺理
You lawyers just like to argue
一枝笔能颠倒是非
You can turn right to wrong
要不然怎么样？
Of course
总不能见死不救呀
I've got to help others
我这个人最喜欢打抱不平
I love to help
你看见了
You saw her
刚才那小娘儿们长得多水亮
That girl looked pretty
偏偏嫁给了那么个老家伙
And she's married to an aged fella
老家伙？
Aged fellow?
老板
Hello, Boss
什么老家伙
What aged fellow?
老王，老板回来了
Wang, the boss is back
我在跟老板娘说笑话呢
I'm chatting with the lady boss
待会替我煎煎
Brew this herbal drink for me
给我吧
Yes
收帐是吧？
Collecting money?
我去了趟徐州
I've been to Xuzhou
收齐了？
Got it all?
老板，给我
Give that to me, boss
哪有那么好的事
Of course not
我去抹把脸，躺一会，待会别忘了
I'm going to freshen up and lie down, don't forget
知道了
I won't
下次说话小心点，别当仇人讲洋话
Be careful when you open your mouth next time
当心我赏你大耳刮子
...or I'll slap you
别这样，人有失手马有漏蹄
Come on, it's an accident
万一有一天，你出了事…
If something happens to you one day...
出什么事，我出什么事？
What do you mean?
算我没说，谢谢你的笔
Forget about what I said, thanks for your pen
去你妈的
Go to hell
你看你…
What now?
刁师爷
Lawyer Diao...
对不起…
Sorry
要是别人，我真要唾他一脸吐呢
Would have spat on you if you were someone else
老板娘，给你来把夜壶
I want to buy a chamber pot
太大了，您给换一把吧
Too big. Another one
那你自己挑吧
Pick yourself
那是小孩用的
That's for kids
行了，将就着用吧
It's all right
我…我抱歉
Sorry...
唱得挺好的，我也想学这一段
I want to learn
你怎么了？你疯了
What's with you? Are you mad?
我疯了…
I'm mad...
掌柜的，回见
See you
死猫，走，快走
Damn cat
他妈的
Damn it
王八蛋，你往哪儿跑？
Where're you going?
王八蛋，你还走？
Asshole, stop running
谁…谁呀？
Who's that?
张妈
Zhang
老板又犯疑心了，你可得帮帮忙
Help me, the boss is getting suspicious again
不然一会儿拳打脚踢的
Or he'll beat me up
我可受不了
I can't take it
怎么回事？
What happened?
你不要问了
Don't ask
这个送给你
Take this
你一会儿替我躺在被窝里
Go over to my bed in a while
老头要是有什么行动
No matter what the boss does
你可千万不要出声呀
Keep your mouth shut
这…
Then...
去…去呀
Just go
王八蛋
Asshole
臭娘们，我打死你
I'll kill you, bitch
贱货，我打死你
Beat you up good
贱货
Bitch
王八蛋，找你娘去算帐去
Bastard, I'll tell your mom about this
在想什么？还不睡？
What're you doing? Come to bed
你先睡吧
You go ahead
痒死了，给我抓抓
I'm itchy, scratch me
上一点
A little higher
下一点
Lower
左边，对了
That's it
舒服
So comfortable
大锤，来吧
Come on, Dachui
开门…
Open up...
来了…
Coming...
什么事？你们三更半夜的
What's going on? It's late
什么事？他说你养汉子
He said you're cheating on him
对，还说把你打得鼻青脸肿
And that he's beaten you up
头发也给剪了
Cut your hair
什么头发？
What hair?
谁的头发？你剪了谁的头发？
Whose hair?
别活见鬼了，你说
Tell me
这头发是哪个臭婊子的，说呀
Whose hair is this?
真是莫名其妙
Unbelievable
看什么看？
What're you looking at?
你自己在外头拈花惹草反而冤枉我
I think it's the other way round
你说这头发到底是谁的，你说呀
Whose hair is this?
这个不是你的，那是谁的？
Whose?
问你呀
I'm asking you
别装蒜了
Stop the act
你还说打得我鼻青脸肿
You said that you beat me up
我哪儿青了，我哪儿肿了？
Where're the bruises?
对呀，你不能冤枉好人哪
Yes, you can't unnecessarily accuse her
姐姐，妈都急死了
Sister, mom is worried
你要是真有这事，她就先上吊
She'll hang herself if this was true
好呀，你冤枉了我不算
You accused me of cheating
还闹到我娘家去
And you complained to my mother?
我不要活了…
How can I face people now?
姐姐…你不要这样，姐姐
Stop it, sister
别拉着我，不要拦住我
Don't try to stop me
不要这样，姐姐…
No, sister
你们看，这个老不死的
Look at him
不知道跟哪个臭婊子乱扯
I don't know who he's with
脚上还系着红绳呢，算我倒霉
Red string on his toe
不是你倒霉…
You're not unlucky...
算我他妈的不走运
I'm unlucky
你还不走运哪，脚上系着红绳不够
You've a piece of red string on your toe
你头上还想戴着绿帽子呀
And wish your wife to have an affair too!
好…你说得好
Well said
天知地知，你知我知，咱们走着瞧
You know what's going on
你小心点
Be careful
You better be careful
我是要小心点，我就是太大意了
Yes, I will get my proof next time
姓陶的胡说八道
Your husband is full of nonsense
我们姓井的也不是好欺负的
Our family is not going to be bullied around
有什么好听？
What's there to listen, huh?
徐州的那批货后天一定要寄出
Send out the goods to Xuzhou on the day after
还有苏州的那批订单
And for the goods to Suzhou
货也要加紧一点
Better work on those soon
您这回去多久呀？
How long will you be away?
少则十天，多则半个月
10 to 15 days
家里的事情你们要帮着看着点
Take care of things
您放心好了
Don't worry
陶老板，出门呀？
Mr. Tao, going away on trip?
是的…出门去
Yes
来了吗？
Is he here?
来了
Yes
王八蛋，我看你还有什么话说
What have you got to say now?
什么事呀？
What's going on?
绑起来
Tie it up
赶快，赶快想想法子
Hurry, think of something
死人，这个死人
How could he do that to me?
活该，让他去死
He deserves to die
那怎么行呢？一夜夫妻百日恩
You're his wife
怎么能见死不救呢？
You must try to save him
跟那个骚娘们一块
He's now tied with that bitch
叫人家绑在麻袋里有什么法子？
...inside the sack
找刁师爷想想办法
Get Lawyer Diao to think of a plan
干什么的？半夜三更敲状
What do you want? It's late
这是你的？
Yours?
抬进去…
Carry it inside
进去
Go
你总得想一个两全其美的办法
Think of a good plan
救得了王老板
which can save Mr. Wang
也要救得了我们老板娘
And also save my lady boss
两全其美？
A good plan?
两全其美，有了
Got it
你先回去，这事包在我身上
Leave now, I'll take care of it
那就好了，你要多帮忙
Great, thanks
你把衣裳脱了
Strip
把衣裳脱了
Go on, take off the clothes
现在是死马当做活马医
We've got to do what we got to do
我动脑、动嘴、动笔
I'm thinking here
你也得帮帮忙，动一动
And you must do your part
脱衣服干什么嘛？
Why do you want me to strip?
事不宜迟，等我解释清楚了
We don't have much time now
恐怕他们两个的命都没了
Otherwise they won't be saved
那你这个忙…我可帮不上了
Then... I won't be able to help
我脱…
Fine...
这不结了吗？
It's not that hard, is it?
你把头回过去，行不行？
Turn your head away
就是要看你嘛
I want to watch
躺下
Lie down
你可别误会
Don't get this wrong
我们得做点痕迹出来
We have to leave some proof
什么痕迹？
Of what?
行过房似的痕迹
That we've had intercourse
你现在就明白了
Now you get it
大人
Your honour
带人犯
Bring in the prisoners
是，带人犯王成龙、陶井氏
Bring in Wang Chenglong, Mrs. Tao
奸夫淫妇带到
The adulterers are here
冤枉…
I've been wronged...
别吵…
Silence...
打开
Open it
是
Yes
冤枉…小民冤枉
I've been wronged...
大人，小民是冤枉的，冤枉啊
Judge, I've been wronged...
王成龙
Wang Chenglong
在
Here
陶井氏
Mrs. Tao
陶井氏…
在
Here
在这儿
Over here
大人
Judge
你是陶井氏吗？
Are you Mrs. Tao?
是
Yes
那麻袋里的女人是谁？
Then who's she?
是王成龙的老婆
Wang Chenglong's wife
王成龙
Wang Chenglong
她是你的老婆吗？
Is she your wife?
是，是小民的老婆周氏
Yes, my wife. Her maiden name is Zhou
我们在家睡得好好的
We were asleep at home
不知道怎么得罪了陶老板
I'm not sure what we had done to offend Mr. Tao
带了几个长工就把我们绑起来了
Mr. Tao came in and tied us up
陶三兴，这到底是怎么回事？
Tao Sanxing, what do you call this?
这…这真是莫名其妙
This... it's all so baffling!
呸，你才莫名其妙呢
Phew! You're the one who's baffling
报告大人
Your honour
前几天他无缘无故的说我跟人通奸
He accused me of having an affair a few days ago
还到我娘家去
He made a scene at my mother's house
把我兄弟哥哥都找来了
Summoned my brothers
报告大人，他是有神经病的
Sir, he's a neurotic
他总是疑神疑鬼的
He has always been suspicious
岂有此理，把陶三兴拉下去
Tao Sanxing will get...
重打四十大板
forty strokes of cane
是
Yes
退堂
End of case
二位点一点
Please count
行了，都是老交情，说了就算了
It's fine
再说我们哥儿俩也不是为了钱
We're not in it for money
我知道…回去吧
I know
谢谢…
Thanks
叫你回去
I've told you to leave
我…
I...
这怎么行呢？
This can't be?
怎么不行呢？
Why not?
当初咱们就这么说好的嘛
We had a deal
再说你欠了债不要你还
And you don't have to pay us
要你老婆还，还不好吗？
Your wife will. Isn't that great?
这…
I mean...
回去吧…
Just go...
你们二位，谁先来呀？
Which one of you wants to go first?
别客气
Come on
哥哥先来
You go ahead
不，你个儿高，你先请
You're taller. After you
不，你比我长几岁，你先来
You're older, after you
兄弟，别客气，你先请
Go on, please
长者先，幼者后，哥哥请吧
The elder first, please
不…  你先请吧
- No... - You first
不…  你请
- No... - Please
你们二位慢慢的让
You two figure it out
我可不客气了
I'll go first
既然这么说，那我不客气了
Then I'm off
好，请吧
Please
勤政爱民
"Be a good civil servant"
后来呢，后来怎么样？
And then what happened?
后来老头回到家里，又气又恨
My husband was angry when he got home
就一病不起
Then he fell sick and died
那王大锤的老婆呢？
What happened to Wang Dachui's wife?
她跟我一样，也在这儿
She's working here too
也在这儿？叫什么名字？
Really? What's her name?
你想打什么主意？
What's on your mind?
伙计…
Waiter...
来了…
Coming...
怎么回事？银娣到现在还没来？
Where's Yindi?
我替您催过了，就到
She'll be right here
再去看看
Go look for her
好…
Yes...
大…
Big...
今天的运气怎么样？
How's your luck today?
快点，银娣
Hurry
来了…
Coming...
我的姑奶奶，人家都等得急死了
Come on, the customer's waiting
急又怎么样？
Let him wait
急了抓子，饿了啃石头
He can take care of himself
快点…把人家等急了
Come on
我一会就来
I'll be right back
去…
Go...
来了
Coming...
讨厌
So annoying!
是你？
It's you?
佩琴
Peiqin
二虎哥
Cousin Erhu
佩琴
Peiqin
二虎哥
Cousin Erhu
你怎么样？好不好？
How have you been?
他们待你好不好？
Are they treating you well?
先别问我，你怎么出来的？
How did you get out?
我偷偷跑出来的
I sneaked out
那怎么可以呢？
How?
要是叫他们捉回去，还得了？
They'll catch you
没有什么得了不得了
No big deal
关在里头看不见你，还不如死了好
I'll take my chances in order to see you
真美
So sweet!
干什么？你们干什么你们？
What are you doing?
别装蒜了，走
Don't feign ignorance; Go
由哪儿来的，还得回到哪儿去，走
Go back to where you belong
放开我…
Let go of me...
走，回去
Go
佩琴
Peiqin
二虎哥
Cousin Erhu
放开我
Let go of me...
二虎哥
Cousin Erhu
佩琴
Peiqin
二虎哥
Cousin Erhu
佩琴
Peiqin
二虎哥
Cousin Erhu
佩琴，你放心
Don't worry, Peiqin
我一定会回来接你出去
I'll come back for you
二虎哥
Cousin Erhu
放开我
Let go of me...
二虎哥…
Cousin Erhu
佩琴
Peiqin
二虎哥…
Cousin Erhu
二虎哥
去看看
Let's check on her
怎么回事呀？那个人…
What's going on? Who's he?
是我表哥，范二虎
My cousin, Fan Erhu
你表哥？
Your cousin?
我从小就许配了给他
I was engaged to him since we were little
后来我爹嫌贫爱富
Then my father opted for wealth
又把我改嫁给高家
He married me off to the Gao family
那孩子小我十几岁
To a husband who's 10 years my junior
玉柱
Yuzhu
爹
Father
你看你看，成何体统？
What are you doing?
一个就要娶妻生子成家立业的人
You're about to get married and start a family
还整天跳跳蹦蹦，跟个孩子一样
How could you behave like a child?
不成器
What kind of a person will you turn into?
少爷就快做新郎倌了
The young master is about to be a groom
大概一时高兴
I think he's just very happy about it
爹，是我叫哥哥陪我玩的
Father, I asked him to play with me
不许你多嘴
Shut up
跟我来
Come with me
一个就要娶妻生子了
You're about to get married...
成家立业的人
and start a family
整天跳跳蹦蹦的
Bouncing around whole day
像个孩子一样，不成器
So childish! This just isn't done
玉柱
Yuzhu
桃之夭夭，灼灼其华
After one gets married, one gets along well...
之子于归，宜室宜家
with the in-laws and starts a family
后天是你跟韩家小姐成亲的日子
The day after tomorrow is your wedding
韩家是本地的望族
The Hans are a respectable family
书香门第，诗礼传家
A family of scholars
佩琴小姐又是有名的才女
Miss Peiqin is a learned lady
今年二十四岁
She's twenty four
二十四岁，比我七妈都要大一岁
24? She's a year older than my seventh mom
不许胡说
Nonsense
老爷，您的鹿血炖好了
Master, the virility supplement is ready
柯大奶奶怎么说？
What did Mrs. Ke say?
她说马上就来
She'll be here soon
柯大奶奶见多识广
Mrs. Ke is a well-informed lady
所以我请她来教你新婚的仪点
That's why I invited her here. I mean,
做你洞房的规范
to teach you about the bedroom etiquette
你要好好的学习
You must pay attention
老爷，您请柯大奶奶教少爷行房？
Mrs. Ke is teaching the young master about sex?
另外替天柱量一量能不能行房
And see if he's ready to have sex yet
行房？这我怎么不会呀
Have sex? Of course I can
刚才还跟玉珍行房来着
I've just tried it with Yuzhen
什么？
What?
在地下跳
Jumping on the ground
那叫跳房子，不叫行房
That's not what it is
混帐，简直混帐
Simply ridiculous
行房跟跳房子都分不清
You should be more careful
要不好好的教教他
If we don't teach him properly, then he'll...
在人家韩小姐面前岂不贻笑大方
make a fool of himself in front of Ms Han
少奶奶会原谅少爷的
She'll of course forgive him
老爷，您刚才说柯大奶奶量得出
Master, you said that Mrs. Ke can tell
少爷能不能行房？
whether the young master's ready or not
她说量得出
She said she can...
从脖子就这么一绕
Around the neck once
然后再这么一折
Put this in half
从鼻子头横量到耳朵边
Measure from the nose to the ear
要是过了耳朵边就能够行房了
He's ready if it passes the ear
不然的话…
Otherwise...
不然的话少爷的婚期
He'll have to postpone his wedding
恐怕就要押后了
...to a later date
当初光绪爷就是破身子太早
Emperor Guangxu became sexually active too young
所以老早就不行了
That's why he was impotent
这也是书上写的？
It's recorded in the book?
这是千真万确的
Absolutely
当初教光绪爷行房的
The Emperor Guangxu...
一共有四位大奶奶
had four sex education teachers
其中的一个就是我三姑
One of them was my Third auntie
一个就是我四姨
Another my fourth auntie
不得了…这哪像是八岁的孩子
Unbelievable! Is he really 8 years old?
虎父无犬子
Like father, like son
可不是吗？您的大名叫得好
Right, you have a good name
高天得，得天独厚嘛
Gao Tiande, meaning the blessed one
恭喜您了，我看不出一年
Congratulations! I think...
准给您生个白白胖胖的大孙子
you will have a grandson within one year
这孩子真淘气
He's a naughty boy
那要看师父的本领
Let's see how good the teacher is
可不能这么说呀
That's not fair
师父领进门，修行可在个人
Teacher can teach, but the student must learn
名师出高徒这句话总不会错吧
An accomplished pupil must have a good mentor
咱们两个丑话可说在头里
We don't have to go into this
食色性也，孔夫子也不能反对
Man's lust for food and sex is natural
不过什么事都不能过量
Nothing can be excessive... especially sex
尤其是房事，所以养生节育
that involves staying healthy and birth control
有一定的界期和无定的界期
There are certain dates
另外加上天忌地忌人忌
I mean... during the year
一年有一百零一天不能行房
There're 101 days you can't have intercourse
另外立春立秋，夏至冬至
Then during First day of Spring
甲子庚生日，夏至后的鼎金日
First day of Autumn
冬至后的庚辛日、舍日、腊日
Summer solstice, winter solstice
天空日、夫妇元辰本应日
And on a few particular festivals
大月的十七跟小月的十六
During the middle of a month; all these days
都是戒日，不能行房
you must refrain from having intercourse
你要记住了，免得老来受苦
Remember... or you'll suffer when you're old
腰酸腿疼，又咳嗽又喘
You'll be in pain, coughing all the time
你看是不是？
Do you agree?
好了
All right
开始上课吧
Let's begin
开始吧
Let's start
柯大奶奶，开始吧
Please start, Mrs. Ke
怎么？
Sorry?
开始吧
Please start
你们要旁听
You want to listen too?
对不起，我是法不传六耳
Sorry, this lesson is meant as one-to-one
有人在，不便说
No third party
我明白…
I understand
高明、张妈，你们都出去
Gao Ming, Gao Ma, leave us
您也不行
You too
对不起
Sorry
哪里…
No problem
你干什么？干什么…起来
What are you doing? Get up
你想要干什么？
What were you thinking?
你不是要行房吗？
Sex, of course
什么？
Pardon?
呸，谁要行房？
Hey, are you mad?
我要行房？我要跟你行房？
With you?
好色小子，想得倒美呀，小兔崽子
Silly brat
起来，把衣服穿上
Get up, get dressed
那怎么教呀？
What then?
先教术科，术科里头要先教术语
Theories and the terms first
离这个真刀真枪的实习
You aren't ready...
还差十万八千里呢
for the real thing yet
你看着呀
Look at this
看见了没有？
Done?
这个就代表你的那个“那话儿”
This represents your willy
我的“那话儿”？我的“那话儿”？
My willy? What willy?
就是你的那个
Your peepee
我的那个…
My...
我的那个叫“那话儿”
My peepee is called a "willy"
那你的那个叫什么话儿？
Then what does your peepee go by?
不像话
Ridiculous
什么不像话
No
你听着，人家韩小姐可是个翰墨人
Listen, Miss Han is so learned
不会粗口粗舌的，所以你要记着
Remember to be civilized
你的那话儿不能叫那话儿
You can't say peepee or willy
那叫什么？
What then?
名称可多了，所以你要记着
There're many ways to call it
可不能在媳妇面前透着没学问
Just observe the proper etiquette
也不能叫阳具，太粗俗了
Not the prick, too vulgar
要叫人道
The penis
再文艺一点叫马藏
Or the member
麻将呀
Member of what?
什么麻将，还牌九呢
Not that kind of member
叫马藏
The member
马藏
叫竹迎
The private part
竹迎
叫鱼翘
The Phallus
鱼翘
Phallus
叫惠穴
Genitals
惠穴
叫士峰
Pecker
士峰
知道了吗？
Got it?
知道了
Got it
记住了吗？
Have you memorized?
记住了
Yep
好，那么咱们再重复一次
Let's repeat
这个叫…
This is called...
叫…
A...
叫什么？
What?
叫手绢
Handkerchief
大玉，柯大奶奶在讲课
Dayu, Mrs. Ke is teaching
不要吵，快回去
Keep quiet, leave
男有五常，女有五欲
The male has 5 principles; & the female- 5 desires
男有七损八益
You must practise sex correctly
女有九气十斗
Only then can both partners benefit
交结之道虽然日新月异
Although there are many styles
归纳起来只有九法
Most well known being the 9 ancient styles
一龙翻、二虎步、三猿搏
Dragon, Tiger, Ape
四蝉腹、五龟腾、六兔吮毫
Cicada, Turtle, Rabbit
七凤翱翔、八鱼接鳞、九鹤交颈
Phoenix, Fish and Crane
以你现在的年龄，要以不变应万变
At your age, just go with the flow
男为阳，女为阴
Male is Yang, female is Yin
天为阳，地为阴
Heaven is Yang, earth is Yin
日为阳，月为阴
Sun is Yang, moon is yin
所以在你新婚的日月里
After you're married pay your respects...
拜完天地至于行天地日月之法
to the gods before you engage in intercourse
天在上，地在下
The heaven is above, earth below
日在上，月在下
The sun is above, moon below
也就是说你在上，韩小姐在下
You're on top, Miss Han under
否则就要五劳七伤
Otherwise you'll be hurting yourself
五劳七伤？真的？
Really?
真的
Yes
糟了
Oh no!
什么糟了？
What?
大玉害死我了
Dayu has done it wrong
大玉，谁是大玉？
Who's Dayu?
七姨妈的使唤丫头
The Seventh aunt's maid
她怎么害你？
What has she done?
大玉每次跟我行房都是她在上面
She's on top every time!
新娘子
Here's the bride
张妈，快点拿火盆来
Zhang, get the fire pan
来了…
Coming...
快…
Hurry
快点
来了…
Coming...
新人跨火盆，大人生小人
Over the fire, blessed with children
新人跨马鞍，黄金堆满山
Over the saddle, blessed with lots of gold
早生贵子
To bear children soon
还有桂圆
Longans
圆圆荔枝
Lychees
协同到老
Happily together ever after
恭喜
Congratulations
老爷，恭喜您了
All the very best
这回你可高兴了
A happy occasion indeed
恭喜少爷、少奶奶
Congratulations
吃呀
Eat up
怎么样呀？生不生呀？
So? Not done?
挺烫
It's hot
没熟嘛
Not done yet
新娘子，生不生呀？
Bride, yes?
怎么生呀？
How?
高老爷，恭喜恭喜
Congratulations
明年抱孙子
You'll have a grandson next year
咱们走吧
Let's go
好呀
Yes
来…
Come on
我也去
I'm going too
咱们到那边去吧
Let's go over there
别吵
Quiet
天在上，地在下
Heaven on top, earth below
日在上，月在下
Sun on top, moon below
我在上，你在下
I'm on top, you're below
不要吵
Keep quiet
叫一叫，要你的命，下床
One sound and I'll kill you. Get down
不要嘛
Don't!
不要…我不要
No...
不要嘛
Please
不要…
No...
我告诉你，我叫范二虎
My name is Fan Erhu
是她的表哥
I'm her cousin
我们俩从小就订了亲
We were engaged since we were little
是她爹嫌贫爱富
Her father opted for wealth
嫁给你，嫁给你这个毛孩子
You were just a kid
我告诉你，今儿个是我跟她洞房
Tonight is our wedding night
乖乖的看着
You sit still
你要是不乖
If you make a sound
我就白刀子进红刀子出
Blood will be on my dagger
听见没有？
You understand?
虎哥
Hu
虎哥？怎么会叫虎哥呢？
Hu? Who's that?
龙精虎猛呀
As strong as a tiger
天在上，地在下
Heaven on top, earth below
日在上，月在下
Sun on top, moon below
我不在上，你在上，笑话
I'm not on top, you're on top; how absurd!
没想到这小子人小鬼大
I'm impressed
包你明年抱个大孙子
You'll have a grandson next year
行，你真行
You're a good teacher
我行有什么用？
Of what good is that?
没有虎父也有虎子
Your son outshines you
五劳七伤
Harmful to your health!
少爷、少奶奶，吃早点了
It's breakfast time, young master and lady
少爷，吃早点了
It's time for breakfast
少爷
Young master
谁？
Who is it?
吃早点了
It's time for breakfast
叫她们放在外面
Ask them to leave the food outside
他们说叫你们放在外面
They said to leave the food outside
他们？
They?
好像有个男人的声音
I heard a man's voice
怎么会呢？
Why's that?
少爷，都快晌午了
Master, it's almost noon
你该起来了
You should get up
再叫
Again
少爷、少奶奶…
Young master, young lady
来了
Coming...
少奶奶早
Morning, young lady
少爷还睡着，让我来
The master's still asleep, let me
少爷
Young master
大玉
Dayu
少爷
Young master
出去
Get out
要是不出去，我就宰了他，滚
I'll beat him if you don't leave. Now scram
你们两个还不滚
Just get out
滚
Out
是…
Yes
你说什么？
What did you say?
少爷给他们绑起来了
They tied up the young master?
老爷，这可怎么办呢？
What should we do now?
老爷，投鼠忌器
Master, we must be careful
少爷在房里不能不小心
They have the young master as their hostage
报官…
Call the police...
来
Come on
站住，叫军队撤出去
Get them out now
不然我就杀了他
Or I'll kill him
爹…
Dad...
各位，请前面商量商量，请…
Everyone, let's talk over there...
二虎哥
Cousin Erhu
不要怕
Don't worry
他们叫咱们过不好
They treat us terribly
咱们也叫他们不好过
We'll do the same
现在他们越不痛快
Now that they're worried
咱们就越痛快，来
We should just enjoy ourselves, come on
告诉他们再要执迷不悟
Tell them to give up
把韩佩琴的父母各打四十大板
Or Han Peiqin's parents will get the cane too
是
Yes
好嘛，打呀
Go on then
打的是他们关我什么事？
They're the ones getting the cane
如果真是痛痒相关的话
If they really love me
他们也不会把我嫁到高家来
They wouldn't have married me here
四十大板？
40 strokes of cane?!
八十大板都解不了恨
Even 80 won't suffice
县长，这…
Sir, then...
老爷，您看这…
Look
不要多嘴
Shut up
小王八蛋，吵什么你
Shut up, little ass
王八蛋，一对狗男女，畜牲
A pair of animals
畜牲，王八蛋？
Animals?
后来呢？把你们怎么样了？
Then what happened?
打了二虎哥一百板子
Cousin Erhu got caned 100 strokes
判了个无期徒刑，把我卖给风月楼
Sentenced to life in prison
你知道第一个到风月楼来找我的
Do you know who's my first customer here?
是谁吗？
Who?
是谁？
Tell us
就是那判案子的县官
The judge for my case
这种人满嘴的仁义道德
Morals and virtues; bloody hypocrites!
满肚子男盗女娼
They are the ones who are the worst
对了，听说你从良了
I heard you've left our line of work
怎么又回来了？
What are you doing back here again?
又回来了？
Back here again?
我在这儿出出进进少说也三次了
I've been in and out of this place thrice
三次？
Three times?
第一次嫁给一个开当铺的倒蛮不错
I was married to a pawn shop owner once
后来为了一棵树，分开了
We separated because of a tree
一棵树？
A tree?
一棵树
A tree
一棵淫树
A tree of sin
其实是一棵梨树
It was actually a pear tree
和普通梨树一样的梨树
Just like any other tree
夏绿秋黄，冬天落叶，春天发芽
It grows normally
可是邓洪发知道
Deng Hongfa knew that
它的确跟旁的梨树不同
...the tree was unique
邓洪发是开当铺的
Mr. Deng opened a pawn shop
有名的守财奴，家里挺有钱的
He's a well known miser, quite well off
喜欢养鹰、喂鸟、打太极
His hobbies include Taichi, keeping birds as pets
这家伙为了找鸟食
In order to feed his birds...
常跑到园子里去找蚱蜢
He often looked for grasshoppers in the garden
这棵树被叫做淫树的由来
The story regarding the tree of sin
是邓洪发在无意中爬到树上发现
happened one day when Deng Hongfa
据说从树上往下看
...looked down from the tree
人人都变成了亚当夏娃了
Everyone under the tree appeared naked
可是在树下景物依然
But it's all normal when not seen from the tree
所以他特别挂了一张木牌子
He put up a notice on the tree
禁止任何人上树
No climbing
其实这全是我变的戏法
Actually it's my trick
你饿了？
Are you hungry?
饿了？
Hungry?
舒服吗？
Comfortable?
舒服
Yes
邓家的大太太去世以后
After his first wife passed away
我被扶了正
...I took her place
你知道了，那个老家伙人老心不老
The old man is quite young at heart
可是有心无力
But he's lousy in bed
于是小玉经常给我穿针引线
My maid Xiaoyu acted as my go-between
反正铺子里的小伙子多的是
There're plenty of young guys in the shop
小蔡
Xiaocai
太太
Madam
什么事？
What?
小蔡说今天有个海员当了个老婆
Xiaocai said a sailor pawned his wife
当老婆？
Pawned his wife?
老婆怎么个当法？
How?
是个不用吃不用喝
One who doesn't need to be fed
也不会争风吃醋的老婆
...and who never gets jealous
乱讲，越说我越不懂了
That's ridiculous
他说西典侠客游记里写过的
It's been written in books
是给航海的人预备的
They are made for the sailors
用橡皮做的，叫做客妻
Made from rubber, called puppet wife
用的时候一吹气就跟真人一样
When you blow it up, it becomes a life size doll
那我倒要开开眼
I want to take a look
小蔡
Xiaocai
干嘛？
Yes?
听说有个海员当了一个橡皮人
I heard a sailor pawned a rubber doll
是呀，这个世界上什么事情都有
Yes, anything is possible
让我看看
I want to take a look
怎么？最好交给我保管
What? I better safe keep it
要不然你们这些年轻小伙子
Otherwise you young lads
偷拿去用用，给人用坏了
...will steal it and ruin it
都打了包了
It's all wrapped up
老板那么凶，谁敢去动？
The boss is mean, no one would dare
别人当然不敢了，你还不敢？
Yes, maybe for the others
不要说是橡皮人，真人你也偷着用
I mean, you ain'tjust stealing the rubber doll!
快给我看看
Quick, let me see
好，跟我来
Okay, come with me
快点
Hurry
我去拿
I'll get it
怎么这么难看？神头鬼脸的
It's horrible!
比你怎么行？
How could it be compared to you?
航海人一走就是十天半个月的
Sailors spend most of their time onboard
总比没有好，你没听说过
Well, something is better than nothing
当兵三年，老母猪都赛貂蝉
Anyone will do when one is desperate
差不多了
Almost
好了吧
Done
你敢
Stop it
最近管楼的小蔡神魂颠倒
Xiaocai has been acting strange lately
魂不守舍
He can't focus on his work
你知道为什么吗？
Do you know why?
魂不守舍？
Not focused?
我…我不觉得
I haven't noticed
你当然看不出来了
Of course you haven't
这几天一见了我
These few days whenever he sees me...
就贼眉鼠眼，鬼鬼祟祟的
He's been acting very sneaky
一定没安着好心眼
I think he's up to no good
不会吧，小蔡在柜上六七年了
Xiaocai has been working for over 6 years now
害人之心不可有，防人之心不可无
One must protect his own interests first
由明天起，你替他管楼
You take over his job starting tomorrow
我…
Me...
先把他调到柜上去，叫他做管理
Send him to manage the front desk
看他几个月再说
Then we'll see after a few months
明天我让他把钥匙交给你
I'll get him to pass you the keys tomorrow
除了我一把之外
I've got my own set of keys
一切可由你负责了
You must be responsible
我…
I...
你可千万要记住了
Remember
对我，对柜上一定要忠心
You must be loyal to me and the company
我会时常试探你的
I'll test you from time to time
忠心，吃用不尽
If you're loyal, you'll be rewarded
不忠心…
If not...
员外这么相信我
You trust me
我怎么会不忠心呢？
Of course I'll be loyal
好，忠心就好
That's good to know
你随我来
Follow me
你先练一练
Practise first
什么事情都是一朝生两朝熟
You'll get used to it
然后熟能生巧
...once you gain more experience
只要细心、小心、当心
Pay attention to details, work seriously
最主要是忠心
Most important is being loyal
是…
Yes...
好呀你
You
怪不得这几天你魂不守舍
No wonder you've been acting strange lately
原来你躲在这儿在偷人哪
You're sleeping with someone here?
是个客人当的，我试试
A customer pawned this, I'm just trying it out
你试试？你这样搞七搞八的
Trying it out?
搞坏了怎么办？你赔得起吗？
You'll ruin it, can you pay for the damages?
是…我好奇
I was... just curious
好奇？你买了鞍子了吗？好奇？
Curious! What kind of excuse is that?
真人你怎么不去骑呢？
Why don't you just find a woman?
赶快洗洗，洗干净点
Clean it up right away
晚上送到我房里去
Send it to my room tonight
对了，从明天起
Right, starting tomorrow
你把钥匙交给郭子祥
Pass the keys to Guo Zixiang
你调到柜上去做管理
You work on the front desk
这儿就由他做管楼，知道吗？
He'll take over, got it?
知道
Yes, boss
走吧
Go
小玉
Xiaoyu
刚才你到哪儿去了？
Where were you?
找了半天都找不着
I've been looking for you everywhere
我不是在这儿吗？
I was right here
给我炖人参汤去
Cook some ginseng soup for me
我没空
I'm busy
干什么？
What?
太太叫我去买东西
The madam has asked me to run some errands
买什么？
What kind of errands?
买瓜子
Buying dried melon seeds
臭嘴，死丫头，总有一天把你摆平
What kind of attitude was that?
来…你们来
Come along...
打打卫生麻将，卫生…
Let's play mahjong
这次太阳可打西边出来了
We are very lucky
咱们员外今天多和气呀
You're in a good mood today
做买卖不和气怎么行呢？
For business one has got to be in good spirits
和气生财嘛
You'll make more when you're in a good mood
二十四圈太多，八圈太少
24 rounds are too much, 8 are too little
干脆十二圈
12 rounds is fine
你们先打着，我去看看帐去
Go ahead, I'll go check on the books
太太，多赢点
I hope you'll win more, dear
你今天应该请客，升了管楼了
You should treat us today, you are promoted
对呀…
Right...
其实今天应该是太太请客
The madam should treat us today
你们看，员外对太太多体帖
The boss loves her so much
当然了，他不对太太体帖
Goes without saying! When he loves her...
太太就会对他体帖了嘛
she will be nicer to him too
我们员外这个人哪
As for my husband, the most...
爱胡子第一，爱鸟第二
he loves his moustache, his pet birds the second
爱他的几颗牙第三
His teeth the third
体帖我呀，黄鼠狼给鸡拜年
He doesn't take me seriously though
没安着好心眼
...unless he needs a favor
碰，胡了，小胡
I win
小胡有什么好胡的
Didn't expect you to win!
小的不去大的不来
Just going with the flow
你倒好，神枪手，专门放冲
Good going! You're cool
小白脸呢？小白脸
Where is the White Dragon?
小白脸就是没好心眼
You're trying to be elusive but anyhow...
可把我想死了
I still adore you
对我要忠心，我会时常试探你的
Be loyal, I'll test you from time to time
小玉，你替我打两把
Xiaoyu, you take my place
死丫头，今天可把你摆平了吧
I'll get even today
小玉，小鼻头小眼，小不点儿
Xiaoyu, your small nose and small eyes
雪白的小脸蛋，没有一个麻子
What a lovely face
真听话，叫你躺着你躺着
You're a good girl, lying down so still
叫你趴着你趴着
So submissive
等会要你的命
I'm going to show you what I've got
雪白的小脸蛋，没有一个麻子
Such a pretty face
小玉，我是大玉，看清楚了没有？
Take a closer look, I'm your wife
怎么样？好不好？
Well? Yes or no?
不错，一定不少钱吧
Must have cost you a fortune
当然了，你要是喜欢的话
Yes, if you like it...
我就送给你
you may have it
别逗了，你哪会那么大方
Are you teasing me? This is from you?
我当然没那么大方了
Of course not
是太太叫我送给你的
The madam gave this to you
太太？
The madam?
说是庆贺你荣升管楼的礼物
A gift for your promotion
真的？
Really?
我骗你干什么
Why would I lie to you?
不过无功受禄寝食不安，对不对？
You'd feel uneasy when you've received a gift
再说嘛
...which you know you don't deserve
得人钱财与人消灾，是不是？
So you should do your part, agree?
消灾？消什么灾？
My part? What part?
你知道，老爷要出门瞻养去了
The boss is going away
过几天才能回来
...for a short trip
她一个人在家怪闷得很
Madam will be bored alone
今儿个晚上叫你陪陪她
Why don't you accompany her tonight?
干什么？打麻将呀？
To do what? Play mahjong?
笨蛋，你跟她两个人
You and her together
两个人干嘛？下棋呀？
Do what? Play chess?
下棋我可不会
I don't know how
两个人能干的事多着呢
There're plenty of things you could do
非得下棋呀
Notjust playing chess
何况关上了房门
When the door is closed...
爱干什么就干什么
You can do whatever you want
上棋下棋，谁管得了你们
No one would care
我明白了
I've got it
你明白了，还算你聪明
At least you're not stupid
一定是老爷叫你来试探我的
The boss sent you to test me, right?
试探你？
Test you?
试探你什么？
For what?
试探我对他忠不忠心
My loyalty
你还以为我不知道
You thought I don't know?
你这个人真是讨厌
You're unbelievable
看你想到哪去了
What are you talking about?
太太是什么样的人你又不是不知道
You should know madam's nature
再说，我是为老爷出卖别人的人？
Am I the type of person to do such a thing?
你真小看了我
That's so wrong of you
好…我相信你，我也不叫你为难
I believe you, I don't want you to get into trouble
要是太太对我真有心的话
If the madam is serious about it
我出个题目难难她
I've a problem for her to solve
什么题目？
What problem?
证明不是老爷试探我
She must prove that the boss isn't testing me
第一，先把老爷喜欢的鸟摔死一只
First, kill one of the boss' birds
干什么？
Why?
别打岔，还有呀
Then
把他的胡子拔下三根
Pluck out three hairs of his moustache
他一共才几根？
He hasn't got many
还有，再把他的牙拔掉一颗
Lastly... take out one of his teeth
不干就不干，我才不跟你闲扯淡
Fine if you're not interested
还真以为天下的男人都死光了
You think you're the last man on earth?
这样让她知难而退
She will give up now
你就不必在这边为难了
And you won't be caught in the middle
有什么了不起
No big deal
天下无难事，只怕有心人
When there's a will, there's a way
告诉他，叫他等着瞧好了
Tell him to wait and see
小玉
Xiaoyu
干嘛？
Yes?
你来
Come here
我没空
I'm busy
比也是白比
You're a champ
胡子留两揪，馄饨四两九
I love my moustache
胡子多几根，餐餐炒肉碎
Dense & thick. Great, isn't it!
德性
Look at you
一个人什么都能有，就是不能有病
One can have anything except sickness
什么都能没有，就是不能没有钱
One can do without anything except money
当然了，谁能比得上你邓洪发呢
Yes, you're quite a man
既有钱，又没病
Rich, healthy
这有什么稀奇的？
What's so unusual about it?
像我这个岁数
People at my age...
有这么好牙口的能有几个？
don't have the sturdy teeth I have
我不是吹牛
I'm not bluffing
我这一辈子就没坐过牙医生的椅子
I've never been to a dentist
再说这胡子多没有用呀
And for my moustache...
要根根见肉
It's unique too
多一根则多，少一根则少
You'll need to have the right amount
大姐，你可知道吗？
You know?
好，真不错，冠军就是冠军
Good, champion is champion
怎么样？
So?
不错…真不愧为冠军
Good, it's the champion
我早就说过
I've told you so
你们比也是白比，是不是呀？
It's clear who's the winner, right?
是…
Yes...
龙就是龙，凤就是凤
So impressive
你们说对不对？
What do you say?
当然…
Of course...
还有，它每天都要洗澡
Needs to be cleaned everyday
矫情极了
So spoiled
一天不给它洗澡就发脾气
Or he'll be in a bad temper
真是的
So crazy
比我那个老婆还难伺候
More demanding than my wife
真是难伺候，矫情
So spoiled
不错
Right...
真是矫情
Exactly
看着…
Look
你们看，正康熙的
Look, from Emperor Kangxi
这几个玩意
These accessories
就已经花了我两千八百块
I've spent a fortune on them
一分钱一分货
But they're worth it
前几天天宝齐有个鸟笼要卖
I saw a bird cage a few days ago
两万六千块
Twenty six thousand dollars
两万六？
Twenty six thousand!
是呀，够买大洋楼的了
One could buy a house with that
他说是乾隆的珍玩
He said it belonged to the Emperor Qianlong
有花宫窑的瓷壶
It's the best porcelain
还有石尘老人的印
With the seal of the famous artist
你干什么？
What are you doing?
干什么？
What?
你…你疯了
Are you mad?
我疯了，我是疯了
Yes I am
我告诉你，自从嫁给你
Since we got married...
没一天好日子过
I haven't had one good day
大老婆活着受大老婆的气
I had to take nonsense from your dead wife before
大老婆死了受你这畜牲的气
And now I have to deal with you!
受你这畜牲的气
I can't stand it
谁给气你受了？这是冠军哪
This is the champion
我的冠军哪
My champ
冠军？
The champion?
在你眼里它是冠军
He is the champ in your eyes
每天天没亮你去遛它
You spend time with him everyday
给它买康熙的壶，每天给它洗澡
Wash him and feed him
你怎么不带我出去遛？
Why don't you spend some time with me?
你怎么不给我买康熙壶？
Why don't you buy antiques for me?
怎么不给我洗澡？
Why don't you bathe me?
你是娶老婆还是娶鸟？
Are you married to your wife or the bird?
我命好苦
I have a tough life
我的天
What a bitter life!
你看…她跟鸟还吃醋呢
I mean, see... she's jealous
这是你的福气嘛，爱呀
I'd say you're blessed, it's love
爱？
Love?
爱
Love
太太，好了…
My dear, well...
好什么？以后再养鸟咱们就离婚
What now? We'll get a divorce if you keep the birds
太太…你…
You...
太太吃醋了，这就是爱情
She is jealous. That's what is love, you know
爱情？她这一爱
Love?
我这两千八百块就玩完了
I've wasted my money
根根见肉，延年益寿
Great moustache, good for longevity
老板，这是上个月的总帐目
Boss, here are the accounts from last month
请您过目
Please take a look
交给太太去
Pass this to the lady
太太，请您过目
Madam, please take a look
等一等，你再说一遍
Wait, say that again
天上一只鹅，地下一只鹅
A goose in the sky, a goose on the ground
我吃鹅蛋，我变鹅
I eat an goose egg, I become the goose
天上一只鹅，地下一只鹅
A goose in the sky, a goose on the ground
我吃鹅蛋，我变鹅
I eat an goose egg, I become the goose
那你再听我说说看，对不对？
Listen to me
这么两句你都不会说，真笨
You've got it wrong, so silly
什么？听的容易
What? It sounds easy
不信，你试试看
Try it yourself
你听着
Listen
等会儿
Hold on
你说不上来呢？
If you can't memorize it...
怎么样？杀头呀
What? I get beheaded?
那倒不必，我们要罚你
No, but we'll punish you
我说上了是不是有赏呀？
Do I get rewarded if I get it right?
当然了
Of course...
怎么赏法？
How?
这样吧，今天我大开方便之门
I'll be generous
要是你说的一字不差
If you can get it right
我就叫小玉亲亲热热的给你亲一下
Xiaoyu will smother you with a kiss
真的？
Really?
小玉，是不是啊？
Yes, Xiaoyu?
我先听听，说得不对怎么罚法
And the punishment?
说得不对
If you get it wrong
每一次拔老爷的胡子一根
A hair plucked from your moustache each time
拔胡子？那怎么行？
Pluck my moustache? No way
那我也不干
Then I won't kiss you
你一毛不拔，谁叫你亲？
If you refuse
好…咱们君子一言
Fine, it's a deal
郭子祥，你作证
Guo Zixiang, you're our witness
你先说一遍
Repeat it
天上一只鹅，地下一只鹅
A goose in the sky, a goose on the ground
我吃鹅蛋，我变鹅
I eat an goose egg, I become the goose
简单得很
It's simple
等一会
Hold on
咱们可是君子一言，不准赖的
You must keep your word
小玉，听见了没有？不准赖的
Xiaoyu, you too
你说嘛
Go on
一二三
One, two, three
天上一只鹅，地下一只鹅
A goose in the sky, a goose on the ground
我吃鹅…
I eat the goose...
我吃鹅干什么呢？不算…
I eat the goose? That didn't count
不行…说话怎么不算数呀
No way
先记着嘛
Drop it down
不行，本小利微概不赊欠
No
真拔？
You'll do this for real?
还客气？小玉，过来拔
Come on, Xiaoyu
好
Sure
真拔？
You'll really pull?
你别想赖，不行
Don't try to get away with it
来吧，再说吧
Come on, again
听着，天上…
Listen...
等等…天上一只鹅，地下一只鹅
A goose in the sky, a goose on the ground
鹅…玩完
Goose... over
又拔一根，来吧…
Another one, come on
要拔拔这边
This side
这一边多一边少，多难看哪
It has to be even
你再说一遍
One more go
听着
Listen well
天上一只鹅，地下一只鹅
A goose in the sky, a goose on the ground
我吃鹅蛋，我变鹅
I eat an goose egg, I become the goose
我吃…我吃鹅蛋干什么呢？真是
I eat... a goose egg?
不算…我认输了…我不来了
I give up, not again
那不行，你得再拔一根
No, the last one
小玉，来
Xiaoyu, come on
又拔，要拔拔中间
Pluck from the middle
好端端的拔什么胡子呢？
What did you do that for?
小玉，给老爷一个安慰奖
Xiaoyu, be good
让他亲一下吧
Let him kiss you
好吧
All right
来
Come on
好臭
It stinks
你说什么？
Excuse me?
老爷的嘴里头有股味
The master has bad breath
胡说八道，我嘴会有味，你闻闻
No way! You smell it
怎么样？我嘴有味吗？
So?
我是已经闻惯了
I think I'm used to it
你自己闻不到就是了
I don't notice it anymore
我早就想告诉你
I've wanted to tell you since long
以前我爸爸也有这个毛病
My father had the same problem
后来一检查
After he went to the dentist
一颗大牙整个都烂空了
...it was discovered that he had cavities
我的牙…
My tooth...
疼不疼？
It hurts?
怎么不疼？
Of course...
现在好点了吗？
Better now?
好点了
A little
拿给我看看
Let's have a look
拿过来
Pass it
靠近点
Closer
这样好吗？
Better now?
这是我的牙？
My tooth?
不像是我的牙
It doesn't look like mine
不是你的，是谁的？
Of course it's yours
怎么？你嘴里长出象牙来吗？
It's your tooth
那我不成了狗了吗？
Am I a dog?
这牙不像是我的
It doesn't look like mine
怎么会呢？
Of course it's yours
拔出来的牙都是这样子的
They all look the same
牙疼不算病，疼起来真要命
It hurts
还有没有味？
Any smell?
有呀
Yes
药味嘛
Smells like medicine
慢慢就没有了
Gradually it'll be okay
不行，我还是不敢
No, I'm still worried
这回你可要我好看了
I'm looking forward to it
好人难做
I'm just trying to be a good guy
这么着吧，再出个题目
How about another problem?
还出题目？
Another one?
难倒她就算了
Just trying to back her off
告诉她，有本事的
Tell her that
叫她当着老爷的面
In front of the master
当着老爷的面？
In front of the master?
当着老爷的面干什么？
Do what?
她想干什么？
Whatever she wants to do
你叫她跟你当着老爷的面…
In front of the master?
好题目，亏你想得出
I'm impressed
好，只要他说得出我就做得到
Fine, I'll do it
不过有一样，他要照我的话去做
He must go with the flow though
后天是观音诞
It's the Guanyin Festival the day after
你看，树上的那些梨那么大了
Look, the pears are huge
还生着呢
Still not ripe yet
我想吃嘛
I want to eat
生梨怎么能吃呢？
It's not time yet
我喜欢嘛
I like it
你真任性
You're really wayward
郭子祥，谢谢你帮我做件事
Guo Zixiang, help me out
上树去摘点梨来
Go get some pears
员外…你们…
Boss, you...
你们光天化日之下怎么可以这样呢
How could you do this here?
我们怎么了？
What about us?
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我们怎么了倒是？
What's wrong with us?
你们…
You...
今天是观音诞你们不怕得罪佛爷
Today is the Guanyin Festival
光天化日之下，这…
and you're like this here...
我们怎么了？你下来…
What? Get down here...
怎么了？
What's going on?
这…真是奇怪了
This... it's strange
奇怪什么？
What?
员外，你怎么又穿上衣服了
You're wearing clothes again?
我怎么没穿衣服？你有毛病呀
Of course I'm dressed, are you crazy?
我穿着好好衣服的
I'm dressed
你说我没有穿衣服？
You said I was naked?
这棵树…
This tree...
这棵树怎么了？
What about it?
员外你不信，你上去看看
You should go take a look yourself
我…
I...
我扶你上去
Let me help you
你们…你们干什么？
What are you doing?
干什么？我们不是好好的嘛
What? We aren't doing anything
你们…你们怎么可以？
How could you?
这…淫树…
This is a tree of sin...
妙，妙极了
Excellent trick
后来那个老家伙每天疯疯癫癫的
Then the old man went berserk
没多久就魂归天国了
...and died soon after
那管楼的呢？
What about the young man?
小白脸可真没好心眼
Heartless man
看着傻里傻气的
He might seem silly...
其实呀，可坏着呢
but actually he's up to no good
怎么了？
What did he do?
跟小玉来了个卷包会
He and Xiaoyu
两个人一块儿跑了
...they ran away together
人心隔肚皮呀
Terrible!
金宝姑娘
Miss Jinbao
小王先生来了
Mr. Wang is here
小王？哪个小王？
Who? Which one?
就是拔牙的那位
The one who took out his tooth
真的？
Really?
金宝…
Jinbao...
金宝
你是哪位？
Who are you?
您贵姓？
What's your name?
怎么了？你连我都不认识了？
Don't you recognize me?
我们这儿有奶就是娘
Any woman could be my mother here
有钱就是大爷，没钱哪…
Any rich man could be my customer, poor man...
金宝…
Jinbao...
我知道，你一定怪我去得太久了
I know I've left for too long
其实我一到了上海马上就往回赶
I came back as soon as possible
你要我买的东西我全买齐了
I've bought everything you wanted from Shanghai
钱也带来了，可是，可是我…
and the money, but I...
可是，半路上遇见强盗了，是吗？
You got robbed on the way, right?
你怎么知道的？
How did you know?
这故事又不是第一次听到
Well, I have heard the story before
你以为好新鲜吗？
An old tale, huh?
这是真的，你不信呀？
It's the truth, you don't believe?
谁说我不信？好了，到此为止了
Yes, I believe you. It's over
你二伯的关王庙
Do me a favor
你找玉堂春唱去吧
Find another Juliet
我可没功夫陪你了
I've no time for you
怎么，你忘了？你忘了我
Have you forgotten about me?
难道你忘了你的头发？
What about your hair?
你可真死心眼
C'mon, give me a break
怎么了，假的？
What? It's fake?
真的？
Really?
要都是真的，风月楼的姑娘
If that's for real...
不个个都变成秃子了吗？
then all the girls here would be bald
那我的牙呢？
What about my tooth?
说来说去，还是为了你的牙
You want it back?
早说嘛
Should have told me sooner
王大爷，天若有情天亦老
Mr. Wang
看开一点吧
Oh, cheer up
您自个儿挑吧
Pick it yourself
我们的牙
Our teeth!
见客了
Come out and greet the guests
楼上楼下，前院后院的姑娘们
Girls from upstairs, downstairs, front and backyards
见客
Greet the guests
来了
Coming
海仙
Haixian
银娣
Yindi
金宝
Jinbao